Finding Aid for A. Alfred Taubman papers, 1942-2014
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Business Investments 1968-2007
  - Irvine Company 1975-1985
    - Litigation: volume containing trial testimony and exhibits relating to AAT probably in case of Kremer vs. Bren et al. (Box 88)
    - Litigation: Deposition of A. Alfred Taubman in the case of The Irvine Company vs. Athalie Irvine Smith and Athalie R. Clarke May 15, 1987 (Box 88)
    - Litigation: various clippings (Box 88)
    - Litigation: correspondence and copies of related documents (Box 88)
  - Michigan Panthers 1980-1985
    The Michigan Panthers subseries provides substantial information on the team from its formation in 1982 through its final season in Michigan and its and merger with the Oakland Invaders. The records document the operation of the team through budget, cash flow, and ticket sales reports; press releases, clippings, and other public relations files; publications, including brochures, schedules, media guides, and yearbooks; stadium and broadcast agreements; and correspondence. The United States Football League (USFL) is documented here through meeting minutes, constitutions and by-laws, publications, and press releases.
    - Cendrowski & Selecky Files
      - A. Alfred Taubman, Correspondence
        - General 1983 (Box 89)
        - Sportsman of the Year 1982-1983 (Box 89)
      - ABC Television Contract (Box 89)
      - Advertising for Michigan Panthers (Box 89)
      - Applications, USFL, Coaching, Promotions, Etc. (Box 89)
      - Argovitz, Jerry, Correspondence (Box 89)
      - Arizona Wranglers (Box 89)
      - Assistant Coaches Agreements, Confidential (Box 244)
      - Bavasi, Peter, Sports Enterprises, Marketing Consultants (Box 89)
      - Birmingham Stallions (Box 89)
      - Bonelli National Sports Consultants (Box 89)
      - Bookkeeper (Box 89)
      - Boston Breakers (Box 89)
      - Budget
        - 1983, 1984 (Box 89)
        - Committee
          - Information, Shire as Budget Committee Chairman, House Meeting (Box 89)
          - USFL Information (Box 89)
          - General (Box 89)
          - USFL Memos per League Meeting (Box 89)
      - Camera, Dom, Correspondence, Licensed Merchandise (Box 89)
      - Campbell, Hugh, USFL Coach (Box 89)
      - Cars, Michigan Panthers (Box 89)
      - Carter, Anthony (Box 89)
      - Cendrowski & Selecky, Michigan Panthers (Box 89)
      - Championship Game, Locations, Correspondence, etc. (Box 89)
      - Channel 50, WKBD TV (Box 89)
      - Charities for Michigan Panthers (Box 89)
      - Check List USFL for all Games (Box 89)
      - Cheerleaders, Half-Time Shows (Box 89)
      - Chicago Blitz
        - Acquisition of, by Walter & Jordan Kaiser & Ron Potocnik (Box 89)
        - Correspondence (Box 89)
      - Committees for League/Members (Box 89)
      - Communications Systems, Cable, Television, Etc. (Box 90)
      - Community Service Program, Players, Coaches Competition (Box 90)
      - Committee Correspondence & Meetings (Box 90)
      - Computers, General Information (Box 90)
      - Conference Calls, Materials Supplied and Topics of Conversation (Box 90)
      - Constitution, USFL (Box 90)
      - Consultants, Consulting Firms Submissions (Box 90)
      - Convention Bureau (Box 90)
      - Corker, John, File, Sports Stars, Pete Huthwaite (Box 90)
      - Corporate Structure, Office & Management (Box 90)
      - Correspondence, Player-Coach-Management (Box 90)
      - Craft-Barressi Consultants, Ltd., Labor Relations for Football Teams (Box 90)
      - CTC Outlet Contract (Box 90)
      - Denver Gold (Box 90)
      - Directory of USFL Teams & Offices (Box 90)
      - Dixon, David F.
        - Correspondence (Box 90)
        - Founders Agreement and Jerry Argovitz Correspondence (Box 90)
      - Doctors, Medical, USFL (Box 90)
      - Dodge for Sponsorship (Box 90)
      - Drafts, Player Allocations, Stocking (Box 90)
      - Equipment (Box 90)
      - Executive Committee, Notes, Correspondence, Meeting Agendas (Box 90)
      - Expansion Committee Meetings & Correspondence (Box 90)
      - Financial
        - Cash Flow Analysis, Revenue/Expenses (Box 90)
        - Payroll, Front Office, Confidential (Box 90)
        - Reporting Systems (Box 90)
        - Source & Application of Funds, Statement of Operations (Box 90)
        - Statements/Proforma Budget (Box 91)
      - Five Year Game Plan for USFL (Box 91)
      - Franchise Information, USFL, 2 folders (Box 91)
      - Free Agent Scouting Combine, USFL (Box 91)
      - Gateway Travel, Championship Game Travel (Box 91)
      - General Manager, File (Box 91)
      - Hadhazy, Peter, Correspondence (Box 91)
      - Hawaiian Franchise (Box 91)
      - Henkel, Robert & Associates, Correspondence (Box 91)
      - Hoffman, Ken, Correspondence (Box 91)
      - Houston Franchise (Box 91)
      - Invoices for USFL (Box 91)
      - Jacksonville Bulls (Box 91)
      - Keller, Mike, Correspondence (Box 91)
      - Kenyon & Eckhardt, Inc., Advertising (Box 91)
      - Kickoff Magazine, Correspondence (Box 91)
      - Konley, Gene, Correspondence (Box 91)
      - LA Express (Box 91)
      - Labor Committee Correspondence & Meetings (Box 91)
      - League Headquarters Personnel Reports Ticket Sales, Etc. (Box 91)
      - League Telexes, General (Box 91)
      - League Office Correspondence (Box 91)
      - Legal Agreements, Documents, By-Laws, Constitutions (Box 91)
      - Logos, Uniforms, Helmets, Colors (Box 91)
      - Lombardi, Vince, Correspondence (Box 91)
      - Lynch, Jayne, Correspondence (Box 91)
      - Magid Study, How the USFL Met Expectations of American Football Fans (Box 92)
      - Malhalab News Service, Photographer (Box 92)
      - Marketing Expenditures, Cendrowski & Thompson Correspondence (Box 92)
      - Marketing Information, USFL (Box 92)
      - Media Strategy, Television & Radio Advertising (Box 92)
      - Meeting Minutes, USFL
        - Miscellaneous (Box 92)
        - Washington D.C., August 30 & 31 1982 (Box 92)
        - Oakland November 10-12, 1982 (Box 92)
        - Tampa, FL December 14-17, 1982 (Box 92)
        - Chicago, IL April 7, 1983, 2 folders (Box 92)
        - Washington, DC May 18, 1983 (Box 92)
        - Chicago, IL, July, 1 1983 (Box 92)
        - Denver, CO July 19-22, 1983 (Box 92)
        - Toronto August 14, 1983, 2 folders (Box 92)
        - Tulsa, OK October 3-7, 1983 (Box 92)
      - Memphis Franchise (Box 93)
      - Michigan Panthers
        - Home Box Office Statements (Box 93)
        - Releases and Correspondence (Box 93)
        - Season Schedule 1983 (Box 93)
      - Miller Brewing Company Sponsorship (Box 93)
      - Miro Miro and Weiner, 823, Inc. (Box 93)
      - Moneys & Reimbursements (Box 93)
      - Morgan, Robert Scott (Box 93)
      - National Football League, Rules, Organizational Structure, Book, etc. (Box 93)
      - New Jersey Generals Correspondence (Box 93)
      - Newspaper Correspondence (Box 93)
      - Oakland Invaders (Box 93)
      - Office Lease and Correspondence (Box 93)
      - Officials, Umpires (Box 93)
      - Oklahoma Outlaws (Box 93)
      - Old Drafts & Documents, USFL (Box 93)
      - Operations Manual 1984 (Box 93)
      - Pacific Select Corporation (Box 93)
      - Pan Am Boeing 727 (Box 93)
      - Panthers Name Research (Box 93)
      - Philadelphia Stars (Box 93)
      - Pinney, Ray (Box 93)
      - Pittsburgh Franchise (Box 93)
      - Players (Box 93)
      - Pontiac Silverdome
        - Agreements, Detroit Lions (Box 93)
        - Astro-Turf Proposal (Box 93)
        - Coaches Offices (Box 93)
        - Leases, 2 folders (Box 93)
        - Stadium Availability 1984 (Box 93)
        - Stadium Information (Box 93)
      - Pontiac Stadium, Lease & License March 16, 1983 (Box 94)
      - Profit Sharing (Box 94)
      - Proformas, USFL (Box 94)
      - Project Sports, Brochure, USFL Substance Abuse Prevention Program (Box 94)
      - Promotions (Box 94)
      - Public Correspondence, General & Friends of AAT (Box 94)
      - Public Relations
        - Clipping Service 1981-1983, 6 folders (Box 94)
      - Purchasing, Uniforms, Equipment, etc. (Box 95)
      - Richmond Bruins Football Organization (Box 95)
      - Rings for Championship Game, 2 folders (Box 95)
      - Ross, Touche, Correspondence (Box 95)
      - Rothbart, Shire, Personal Correspondence (Box 95)
      - San Antonio Franchise (Box 95)
      - San Diego Franchise (Box 95)
      - Season Correspondence 1983-1984 (Box 95)
      - Shareholders Correspondence (Box 95)
      - Signing of Underclassmen Correspondence (Box 95)
      - Simmons, Chet, Commissioner, Correspondence (Box 95)
      - Sims, Billy, Contracts (Box 95)
      - Spavital, Jim, Confidential (Box 244)
      - Spivak, Judge Peter
        - Agreement between AAT & Spivak (Box 95)
        - Confidential File, Shire Rothbart Only (Box 244)
        - Correspondence (Box 95)
      - Stanley, Coach Jim (Box 95)
      - Substance & Abuse Committee, Report (Box 95)
      - Tampa Bay Bandits (Box 95)
      - Tax Information, Price Waterhouse (Box 95)
      - Telephone System, Office (Box 95)
      - Thompson, Jack, Quarterback, Cincinnati Bengals (Box 95)
      - Thompson, John, Confidential (Box 244)
      - Thompson, Tom, Correspondence (Box 95)
      - Tickets, Sales, Marketing, etc. (Box 95)
      - Tiger Stadium Correspondence (Box 95)
      - TV Ratings (Box 95)
      - University of Michigan Correspondence (Box 95)
      - Vital Options, Deana Hawthorne, Information & Quotation (Box 95)
      - Waivers, All Player Rights Only (Box 95)
      - Washington Federals, Confidential (Box 244)
      - Work-Out Agreement, aka "Bail Out" (Box 95)
      - WXYZ Broadcast Agreement (Box 95)
      - Yaffe Berline
        - Broadcasting (Box 95)
        - Grossman, Jim, Confidential (Box 95)
        - Pre-Game Parties (Box 95)
    - Newspaper Clippings from Jayne Lynch Files
      - January-August 1983, 8 folders (Box 96)
      - September 1983-May 1984, 10 folders (Box 97)
    - By-Laws 1982 (Box 98)
    - Championship Season, Review (Box 98)
    - Contracts (Box 98)
    - Correspondence
      - General 1982-1983, 5 folders (Box 98)
      - Fan Mail 1983 (Box 98)
      - Greatways Travel Corp. (Box 98)
      - Western Union Mailgram 1983 (Box 98)
    - Financial
      - General 1982-1985, 2 folders (Box 98)
      - Bank Statements (Box 98)
      - Budget 1982-1984, 3 folders (Box 98)
      - Fisher, Max (Box 98)
      - Keller, Michael (Box 98)
      - Letters of Credit 1982-1984 (Box 98)
      - Miro, Miro & Weiner Trust Account (Box 245)
        [Restricted until January 1, 2032 ]
      - Schedule K-1 1983 (Box 98)
      - Season Ticket Solicitation (Box 98)
      - Spivak, Peter (Box 98)
      - Statements April-November, 1983 (Box 98)
      - Ticket Sales (Box 98)
    - League Meeting December 14-17, 1982 (Box 98)
    - Legal Contracts, 2 folders (Box 98)
    - Miscellaneous, 3 folders (Box 98)
    - Pontiac Silverdome (Box 98)
    - Public Relations
      - Clippings 1982 (Box 98)
      - Clippings 1983-1984, 3 folders (Box 99)
      - Media Releases (Box 99)
      - Network Telecasts (Box 99)
      - Radio Interviews 1983 (Box 99)
    - Taubman, Interview (Box 99)
    - NFL
      - Annual Meeting 1982 (Box 99)
      - Detroit Lions, Sublease & License 1973 (Box 99)
    - NSFL, News Release 1982 (Box 99)
    - USFL
      - Arizona Wranglers (Box 99)
      - Birmingham Stallions (Box 99)
      - Boston Breakers (Box 99)
      - Championship Game 1985 (Box 99)
      - Communications Research (Box 99)
      - Constitution 1982, 2 folders (Box 99)
      - Correspondence
        - General 1981-1985, 6 folders (Box 99)
        - Dixon, David F., 3 folders (Box 99)
      - Detroit Franchise, Interviews Completed (Box 99)
      - Executive Committee 1983 (Box 99)
      - Expansion Agreement 1983 (Box 99)
      - Houston Gamblers (Box 99)
    - League Meeting 1982-1983, 2 folders (Box 100)
    - Legal
      - ABC Contract (Box 100)
      - Case No. 2-RC-19522 (Box 100)
      - Contracts, General (Box 100)
      - Player Contract (Box 100)
      - Simmons, Chet (Box 100)
      - Subscription Agreement 1981 (Box 100)
    - Louisiana Superdome (Box 100)
    - Marketing 1983 (Box 100)
    - Marketing Report 1983 (Box 100)
    - Meeting Minutes November 11-12, 1982 (Box 100)
    - Miscellaneous, 4 folders (Box 100)
    - Oakland Invaders (Box 100)
    - Philadelphia Stars (Box 100)
    - Public Relations
      - Clippings 1980-1984, 5 folders (Box 100)
      - Malhalab News Service (Box 100)
      - News Releases 1982-1983, 2 folders (Box 100)
      - Telephone Conference (Box 100)
    - San Francisco 49ers (Box 100)
    - Season Tickets 1982 (Box 100)
    - Tampa Bay Bandits (Box 100)
    - Usher, Harry, Commissioner (Box 100)
    - Washington Federals (Box 100)
    - Biographic Information on Personnel (Box 101)
    - Correspondence
      - General 1983-1984, 2 folders (Box 101)
      - Robert Henkel & Associates 1983 (Box 101)
      - Rothbart, Shire, Discuss File (Box 101)
      - Thank You Notes 1983 (Box 101)
      - Yaffee Berline 1983 (Box 101)
    - Events
      - Pre-Game Cocktail Party March 19, 1983 (Box 101)
      - Pre-Game Parties, Schedule April 1983 (Box 101)
      - Pre-Game Parties, Media April 17, 1983 (Box 101)
      - Brunch April 23, 1983 canceled (Box 101)
      - Pre-Game Parties May 1983 (Box 101)
      - Special Olympics Volunteer Party, New Jersey May 16, 1983 (Box 101)
      - Easter Seals Party, Birmingham Stallions May 23, 1983 (Box 101)
      - Channel 56 Volunteers Party, Tampa Bay Bandits May 30, 1983 (Box 101)
      - Muscular Dystrophy & Channel 56 Volunteers June 20, 1983 (Box 101)
      - Children's Hospital & Variety Club Volunteers July 3, 1983 (Box 101)
      - Finals, Oakland Invaders, VIP Party July 10, 1983 (Box 101)
      - Pre-Game Championship Brunch July 17, 1983 (Box 101)
      - Manoogian Mansion, Mayor Young August 9, 1983 (Box 101)
      - Governor's Reception January 1984 (Box 101)
      - Pittsburgh Maulers, Governor Blanchard March 3, 1984 (Box 101)
    - Financial, Invoices (Box 101)
    - Logo Sheets (Box 101)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 101)
    - Name Selection (Box 101)
    - Pontiac Silverdome (Box 101)
    - Printed
      - "Frontline, An Unauthorized History of the NFL" (Box 101)
      - Media Guides 1983-1984 (Box 101)
      - Media Guide 1984 (Box 101)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 101)
      - Program, USFL Championship Game July 17, 1983 (Box 101)
      - Review of the Michigan Panthers Championship Season 1983 (Box 101)
      - Yearbook 1983 (Box 101)
      - USFL Kickoff, No. 2, 3, 9 (Box 101)
      - "World Football League-The Tainted Promise" (Box 101)
      - Proclamations (Box 101)
    - Public Relations
      - General 1983, 2 folders (Box 102)
      - Clippings June-December 1984, 5 folders (Box 102)
      - Malhalab News Service 1983 (Box 102)
      - Media Releases 1983-1984, 3 folders (Box 102)
      - Panther Prowlings, Calendar 1983-1984 (Box 102)
      - Radio, Transcripts & Tapes Received (Box 102)
      - Vince Lombardi News Conference October 3, 1983 (Box 102)
    - Quick Facts (Box 102)
    - Schedule 1984 (Box 102)
    - Taubman
      - Press Conference Speech November 18, 1982 (Box 102)
      - Statement August 1984 (Box 102)
      - USFL Statement October 20, 1983 (Box 102)
    - Variety Club 1984 (Box 102)
    - Images, including A. Alfred Taubman and the championship celebration 1983, .ZIP file
  - Sotheby's 1983-2007
    The Sotheby's subseries includes a small amount of board of directors' files, including correspondence, meeting minutes, and financial reports; information about auction locations in Milan, Paris, and Tokyo; legal documents and correspondence related to Taubman's indictment; Taubman's calendars and itineraries; and clippings and photocopies of news stories, articles, and book chapters about Taubman's acquisition of Sotheby's and the anti-trust litigation. Testimonial letters sent to the court prior to Taubman's sentencing can be found in the Personal series.
    - Litigation, Articles About (Box 103)
    - Settlement Agreement Documents (Box 103)
    - Taubman Assets Group Subpoena (Box 103)
    - Miscellaneous Projects (Box 103)
    - Financial Events 1991-2000 (Box 103)
    - Dun and Bradstreet Reports re AAT Indictment (Box 103)
    - Court Documents (Box 103)
    - AAT Calendar 1999-2000 (Box 104)
    - AAT Itinerary 1997 (Box 104)
    - AAT Personal Correspondence (Box 104)
    - Beverly Hills (Box 104)
    - Board of Directors and Shareholders (Box 104)
    - Class Action Suit (Box 104)
    - Clippings 1994-2002, 4 folders (Box 104)
    - France (Box 104)
    - Japan (Box 104)
    - Legal Briefs (Box 104)
    - Legal Correspondence (Box 104)
    - Milan (Box 104)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 104)
    - New Bond Street (Box 104)
    - Auditor's Report 1987 (Box 105)
    - Board Minutes 1999 (Box 105)
    - Capital Plan 1989-1993 (Box 105)
    - Compensation Program 1985 (Box 105)
    - Correspondence 1996-2007 (scattered), 2 folders (Box 105)
    - Defendant's Exhibits (Box 105)
    - Guide to Titles, Ranks, etc. (Box 105)
    - Jeffrey Hogrefe, "Wholly Unacceptable" (Box 105)
    - Robert Lacey, "Sotheby's: Bidding for Class" (Box 105)
    - Phone Directory (Box 105)
    - Shareholders (Box 105)
    - Stock Sales (Box 245)
    - Peter Watson, "Sotheby's: The Inside Story" (Box 105)
    - Clippings 1993-2001, photocopies (Box 106)
    - Clippings 2002, photocopies (Box 107)
    - Sotheby's Public Offering 1988 (Box 107)
    - Photocopy of Nicholas Faith's SOLD, The Revolution in the Art Market ( 1985 ) with letters by Christopher J. Tennyson containing corrections regarding AAT's acquisition of Sotheby's, 1985 (Box 107)
    - Art and Antiques"Top 100 Collectors in America" 1989, 1991, 1992 (Box 107)
    - Corporate Affairs Department (Christopher J. Tennyson, Director)
      - Article Files
        - Detroit Free Press, September 19, 1985: "The Business of Art" (Box 108)
        - Detroit Free Press, September 18, 1985 from Wall Street Journal, "Like a War/Art World" (Box 108)
        - Wall Street Journal, September 18, 1985 by Meg Cox, "Selling Art/Root Beer" (Box 108)
        - New York Times, June 19, 1983 by Isadore Barmash, "Sotheby's White Knight with a Picasso" (Box 108)
        - The Antique Collector, May 1984 "Sotheby's New Owner, A. Alfred Taubman" (Box 108)
      - Background (Box 108)
      - Sotheby's Prospectus (Box 108)
      - "Notes on the History of Sotheby's" 1917 (Box 108)
      - AAT Stock Sale (Box 108)
      - AAT Sotheby's Announcement (Box 108)
      - Sotheby's Hebrew Manuscripts/Judaica, 2 folders (Box 108)
      - Sotheby's Correspondence 1988, 1997, 2 folders (Box 108)
      - Consumer Affairs Investigation (Box 108)
      - Bond Controversy (Box 108)
      - Public Offering (Box 108)
      - "A Study of Sotheby's Public Relations" by Christopher J. Tennyson 1984 (Box 108)
      - Sotheby's Trial Press Coverage/Original Article Clippings 2000-2001 (Box 108)
    - Sotheby's Holdings, Inc. Private Placement, Term Loan and Revolving Credit Facility 1985 (Box 109)
    - Images and articles 1983-2003, .ZIP file
  - Directorships and Other Investments 1968-1994
    The Directorships and Other Investments subseries documents Taubman's service on the boards of directors of United Brands (1977-1984), Chase Manhattan Corporation (1986-1988), and R.H. Macy Company (1986-1994). These files include meeting minutes, financial reports, and board correspondence. This series also includes a small number of records related to Taubman's investments in American Exploration Co., Broadcast Group, and Florida Extrusion/Florida Billet/National Shower Company. Note that the Topical series includes additional records of Taubman's investments.
    - United Brands
      - Audit Plan 1978 (Box 110)
      - Board of Directors Meeting June 22, 1977 (Box 110)
      - Board of Directors Meeting August 19, 1977 (Box 110)
      - Board of Directors Records 1968-1979, 7 folders (Box 110)
      - Board of Directors Records 1979, 5 folders (Box 111)
      - Board of Directors Meeting Records 1979, 9 volumes (Box 112)
      - Organizational Manual 1979 (2 copies) (Box 112)
      - Audit Plan 1979 (Box 112)
      - Financial Reports (Box 113)
      - Securities and Exchange Commission Form 10-K (Box 113)
      - Securities and Exchange Commission Form 4 (Box 113)
      - Annual Reports to Shareholders and Employees (Box 113)
      - Securities and Exchange Commission Questionnaire for Directors and Executive Officers 1983-1984 (Box 113)
      - AAT stock sales (Box 113)
      - Purchase of New Energy Corporation of Indiana 1980 (Box 113)
      - Board of Directors Reports and Communications 1979-1980, 2 folders (Box 113)
      - Board of Directors Reports and Communications 1981-1984, 7 folders (Box 114)
    - Chase Manhattan Bank
      - Board of Directors Meeting Binders
        - 1986-1987 (Box 115)
        - 1986-1987 (Box 116)
        - January-August 1988 (Box 117)
        - September-December 1988 (Box 118)
      - Trust and Investment Committees Agendas March 1988 (Box 118)
    - R.H. Macy
      - Board of Directors
        - Questionnaires 1986-1993 (Box 119)
        - Correspondence and Reference Materials 1986-1994, 10 folders (Box 119)
        - Correspondence and Reference Materials 1994, 2 folders (Box 120)
        - Annual Report 1985 (Box 120)
        - Board of Directors Agendas 1988 (Box 120)
        - Board of Directors Earnings Reports 1988 (Box 120)
    - A&W Restaurants
      - Chronological 1987-1995, 9 folders (Box 120)
      - Clippings 1982 (Box 120)
      - Images 1984-1990, .ZIP file
    - American Exploration Co. (Box 121)
    - Broadcast Group (Phoenix Stations) miscellaneous (Box 121)
    - Florida Extrusion Inc., Florida Billet Inc., National Shower (Box 122)
- University Endowments 1977-2007
  The University Endowments series contains files on Taubman's major contributions to American universities. Materials related to the A. Alfred Taubman Center for Public Policy & American Institutions at Brown University include correspondence, annual reports and brochures from the Center, a copy of the speech Taubman gave at the Center's 1985 Dedication, and photographs of the ceremony and facilities. Materials documenting the A. Alfred Taubman Center for State and Local Government at Harvard University's Kennedy School include correspondence, construction photographs, Taubman's speech at the 1988 cornerstone laying, advisory board minutes, and a small number of published items. Materials related to the Taubman Program in American Institutions at the University of Michigan include correspondence, reports, and a 1985 speech by Taubman. The planning work Taubman did on behalf of Michigan's University Hospital is documented through notes and minutes of the Planning Advisory Committee (1977-1981) and space planning reports. The series also includes board meeting minutes, reports, and correspondence from Taubman's time as chairman of the Advisory Board of the Zell/Lurie Real Estate Center at the Wharton School.
  - Brown University, A. Alfred Taubman Center for Public Policy & American Institutions
    - Correspondence and Other Papers 1980-1999, 7 folders (Box 123)
    - Annual Reports 1984-1999 (Box 123)
      (some gaps)
    - Brochures (Box 123)
    - "How America Works: A Comparative Understanding of American Institutions -- Public and Private" Speech by AAT at the Dedication of the A. Alfred Taubman Center for Public Policy and American Institutions, Brown University April 12, 1985 (Box 123)
    - Evaluation of Taubman Programs in American Institutions at Brown undertaken by Nathan O. Hatch (Notre Dame) and Craig Hammon (Center for New Era Philanthropy) 1985 (Box 123)
    - Center for New Era Philanthropy Miscellaneous (Box 123)